<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>boox on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/tags/boox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in boox on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/tags/boox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting SuperNote files to PDF</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is my primary mode of note taking and at the beginning of the
pandemic, I switched from paper notebooks to digital notebooks. My primary
notetaking devices are SuperNote A6X, Boox Max3, and iPad Pro using Notability
App (in that order,
though I do prefer iPad for reviewing papers etc. because of the speed). I
prefer the writing experience on Supernote, but I do miss one of the software
features of Boox: In Boox, everytime I save a note file, it is automatically
converted to PDF and stored in a pdf directory which mirrors the layout of the
notes directory. There is no such feature in SuperNote. Notes have to
converted manually and get exported to a flat directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tale of two eink notebooks</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/tale-of-two-eink-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/tale-of-two-eink-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a pen and paper person. On a typical day, I write about 10&amp;ndash;30
handwritten pages. (I write on a half-folded printer paper, so it is actually
only 7-15 pages &amp;ldquo;full&amp;rdquo; pages). For the last decade or so, I have written
almost exclusively using fountain pens (Pelikan M200, Pilot Vanishing Point,
and occasionally, Pilot Metropolitan).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce the amount of time I state at a screen, I purchased a &lt;a href=&#34;https://onyxboox.com/boox_max3&#34;&gt;Oynx Boox
Max3&lt;/a&gt; tablet almost a year ago, primarily to read academic PDFs. The
13.3&amp;quot; screen of Max3 is perfect for reading dense IEEE formatted two-column
PDFs. Max3 is an Android device and many Android apps work reasonably well on
it. So, I ended up using it for internet browsing, reading emails and Slack
messages, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ereader/comments/fnxkep/using_boox_max3_as_a_whiteboard_for_teaching/&#34;&gt;delivering zoom lectures&lt;/a&gt;, and even watching Youtube videos!
Clearly, J.K. Rowling had Max3 in mind when she described the newspapers with
moving pictures in Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
