<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cron on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/tags/cron/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cron on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/tags/cron/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting SuperNote files to PDF</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is my primary mode of note taking and at the beginning of the&#xA;pandemic, I switched from paper notebooks to digital notebooks. My primary&#xA;note taking devices are SuperNote A6X, Boox Max3, and iPad Pro using Notability&#xA;App (in that order,&#xA;though I do prefer iPad for reviewing papers etc. because of the speed). I&#xA;prefer the writing experience on Supernote, but I do miss one of the software&#xA;features of Boox: In Boox, every time I save a note file, it is automatically&#xA;converted to PDF and stored in a pdf directory which mirrors the layout of the&#xA;notes directory. There is no such feature in SuperNote. Notes have to&#xA;converted manually and get exported to a flat directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backup up data</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/backing-up-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/backing-up-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For about 10 years now, I have been using Dropbox as a tool to synchronize data&#xA;between my work desktop and my laptop. I do a local backup using&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rsnapshot.org&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsnapshot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but they were only stored locally on my desktop. So,&#xA;effectively, I had been relying on Dropbox as a backup solution. Every so&#xA;often, I read horror stories that &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=dropbox+is+not+a+backup+solution&#34;&gt;Dropbox is not a backup solution&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;And every time I would read one of these reports, I would think, &amp;ldquo;Hmm&amp;hellip; maybe&#xA;I should start using a proper backup solution.&amp;rdquo; I finally bit the bullet and&#xA;purchased some storage from &lt;a href=&#34;http://rsync.net&#34;&gt;rsync.net&lt;/a&gt; and set up a back up&#xA;system. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
