<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying out hledger</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-hledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-hledger/</guid>
      <description>As an academic, I need to track research funds: what is the remaining balance of each grant, how much I have committed for student stipends, what are anticipated expenditures for conference travel, etc. Like everyone else, I used to do this via a spreadsheet, but my spreadsheet was becoming a bit too complicated. So, I decided to try plain text accounting, and use hledger to keep tracks of research funds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing dotfiles using stow</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/managing-dotfiles-using-stow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/managing-dotfiles-using-stow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions was to come up with a sensible way to manage
my dotfiles. I evaluated a few solutions and finally settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/stow/&#34;&gt;GNU
stow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting SuperNote files to PDF</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/converting-supernote-files-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is my primary mode of note taking and at the beginning of the
pandemic, I switched from paper notebooks to digital notebooks. My primary
note taking devices are SuperNote A6X, Boox Max3, and iPad Pro using Notability
App (in that order,
though I do prefer iPad for reviewing papers etc. because of the speed). I
prefer the writing experience on Supernote, but I do miss one of the software
features of Boox: In Boox, every time I save a note file, it is automatically
converted to PDF and stored in a pdf directory which mirrors the layout of the
notes directory. There is no such feature in SuperNote. Notes have to
converted manually and get exported to a flat directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing PDFs via command line</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/signing-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/signing-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Signing PDFs in Linux is always a PITA. Part of the reason is that Adobe
stopped the development of a linux port of Adobe Reader since adobe reader v9.
Some of the newer PDFs require features which are newer than acrobat v9 and
cannot be opened or signed with acrobat v9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this page, I summarize some of the options for signing PDF that have worked
for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local config for kitty</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in the last post, I am testing out kitty as my terminal emulator instead of UXTerm. So for everything has been smooth sailing except for one minor issue. On my work desktop, I want fontsize 11 but on my laptop, I want fontsize 14. This is a combination of resolution and physical size of the two monitors. Reading the documentation of kitty.conf, it was not clear how to set conditional values for the variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing terminal and browser</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time on the terminal: using alpine to send emails and using vim/neovim to edit tex files and code. For at least a decade if not longer, I have been using UXTerm as my terminal emulator. At some stage I spent some time configuring UXTerm fonts and color schemes to what I like, and I have been using it ever since. Recently, I started experiencing some weird issues with UXTerm, which forced me down a rabbit hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out Visidata</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</guid>
      <description>Normally, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with large spreadsheets. I do use simple spreadsheets for keeping track of budgets/investments/taxes etc., but the only big spreadsheets I encounter are sifting through all applicants for hiring students and assigning grades to students. I struggle through OpenOffice Calc to work through these, because navigating spreadsheets is too slow.
I recently came across a recommendation for visidata in a thread of HackerNews, and it certainly looks like a program that I should checkout the next time I need to work through a big spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out qutebrowser</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/qutebrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/qutebrowser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been cycling between web browsers for the last few years. I used to use
Opera, but then it became a shell for Chrome, then I started using Chromium,
but occasonally got huge memory consumption, then I started using Firefox, but
lately it has become very laggy (to the extent that even scrolling was slow).
So, after testing a bunch of less commonly used browsers, I have finally
settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://qutebrowser.org/&#34;&gt;qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Slack from the terminal</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In rencent years, lot of my short conversations with my research lab has moved
to Slack. I am not a big fan of closed protocol communication clients, but
Slack has the advantage that it is relatively easy to use. Well, it seems that
it relatively easy to use for everyone except me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing newest file in a directory</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/accessing-newest-file-in-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/accessing-newest-file-in-directory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many instances where I want to access the most recent file in a
directory:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
