<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:35:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing out Visidata</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</guid>
      <description>Normally, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with large spreadsheets. I do use simple spreadsheets for keeping track of budgets/investments/taxes etc., but the only big spreadsheets I encounter are sifting through all applicants for hiring students and assigning grades to students. I struggle through OpenOffice Calc to work through these, because navigating spreadsheets is too slow.
I recently came across a recommendation for visidata in a thread of HackerNews, and it certainly looks like a program that I should checkout the next time I need to work through a big spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out qutebrowser</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/qutebrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/qutebrowser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been cycling between web browsers for the last few years. I used to use
Opera, but then it became a shell for Chrome, then I started using Chromium,
but occasonally got huge memory consumption, then I started using Firefox, but
lately it has become very laggy (to the extent that even scrolling was slow).
So, after testing a bunch of less commonly used browsers, I have finally
settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://qutebrowser.org/&#34;&gt;qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Slack from the terminal</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In rencent years, lot of my short conversations with my research lab has moved
to Slack. I am not a big fan of closed protocol communication clients, but
Slack has the advantage that it is relatively easy to use. Well, it seems that
it relatively easy to use for everyone except me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing newest file in a directory</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/accessing-newest-file-in-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/accessing-newest-file-in-directory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many instances where I want to access the most recent file in a
directory:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup up data</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/backing-up-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/backing-up-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For about 10 years now, I have been using Dropbox as a tool to synchronize data
between my work desktop and my laptop. I do a local backup using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rsnapshot.org&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsnapshot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but they were only stored locally on my desktop. So,
effectively, I had been relying on Dropbox as a backup solution. Every so
often, I read horror stories that &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=dropbox+is+not+a+backup+solution&#34;&gt;Dropbox is not a backup solution&lt;/a&gt;.
And every time I would read one of these reports, I would think, &amp;ldquo;Hmm&amp;hellip; maybe
I should start using a proper backup solution.&amp;rdquo; I finally bit the bullet and
purchased some storage from &lt;a href=&#34;http://rsync.net&#34;&gt;rsync.net&lt;/a&gt; and set up a back up
system. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tale of two eink notebooks</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/tale-of-two-eink-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/tale-of-two-eink-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a pen and paper person. On a typical day, I write about 10&amp;ndash;30
handwritten pages. (I write on a half-folded printer paper, so it is actually
only 7-15 pages &amp;ldquo;full&amp;rdquo; pages). For the last decade or so, I have written
almost exclusively using fountain pens (Pelikan M200, Pilot Vanishing Point,
and occasionally, Pilot Metropolitan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reduce the amount of time I state at a screen, I purchased a &lt;a href=&#34;https://onyxboox.com/boox_max3&#34;&gt;Oynx Boox
Max3&lt;/a&gt; tablet almost a year ago, primarily to read academic PDFs. The
13.3&amp;rdquo; screen of Max3 is perfect for reading dense IEEE formatted two-column
PDFs. Max3 is an Android device and many Android apps work reasonably well on
it. So, I ended up using it for internet browsing, reading emails and Slack
messages, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ereader/comments/fnxkep/using_boox_max3_as_a_whiteboard_for_teaching/&#34;&gt;delivering zoom lectures&lt;/a&gt;, and even watching Youtube videos!
Clearly, J.K. Rowling had Max3 in mind when she described the newspapers with
moving pictures in Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to ZSH</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/back-to-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:53:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/back-to-zsh/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in a previous post, I started using fish after using zsh for about 15 years. After working exclusively on fish for about 3 months, I am now back to zsh.
In the end, there was nothing inherently missing in fish, but fish just did a few minor things differently which began to get annoying.
 Fish&amp;rsquo;s tab-completion first shows a short list of option (top 10 or so) and you have to press tab twice to see the whole list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing using rclone</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/syncing-using-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/syncing-using-rclone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been a Dropbox user for over a decade. Part of the attraction for me
was that it is one of the few synchronization services that fully supports
Linux. I had it installed on two servers, my office desktop, my laptop, and
most of my mobile devices. Couple of years ago, my employer moved most of its
IT services with Microsoft 365, which gives me access to storage space on
Microsoft OneDrive as well. Plus, I have purchased additional storage on
Google (for backing up my personal photos). But I never seriously used
Microsoft OneDrive or Google Drive for synchronization because all my computers
run Linux and neither of these services had a Linux client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Fish Shell</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-fish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; as my shell for almost 15 years. I spent ages
configuring it in the beginning and for the most part I have been happy with
my setup. Lately, I saw multiple suggestions for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-autosuggestions&#34;&gt;zsh-autosuggestions&lt;/a&gt;, which
has a tag-line &amp;ldquo;Fish-like autosuggestions for zsh&amp;rdquo;. Imitation is the best form
of flattery. So, I thought of giving fish a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and using multiple versions of a library</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/multiple-versions-of-a-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 13:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/multiple-versions-of-a-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use a Haskell static website generator called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/yst&#34;&gt;yst&lt;/a&gt; for generating my
homepage. Why? Partly because when I first created my professional webpage, I
was a Haskell enthusiast and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/yst&#34;&gt;yst&lt;/a&gt; seemed cool. After a while, I got
frustrated with Haskell (I use Arch Linux, and it seemed that each upgrade
would break Haskell install) and moved on. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used Haskell for a while
now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
