<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLI on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/categories/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLI on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/categories/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying out hledger</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-hledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-hledger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an academic, I need to track research funds: what is the remaining balance of each grant, how much I have committed for student stipends, what are anticipated expenditures for conference travel, etc. Like everyone else, I used to do this via a spreadsheet, but my spreadsheet was becoming a bit too complicated. So, I decided to try plain text accounting, and use &lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org/&#34;&gt;hledger&lt;/a&gt; to keep tracks of research funds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- more --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hledger&lt;/code&gt; may be considered as a Haskell port of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ledger-cli.org/&#34;&gt;ledger&lt;/a&gt;, though there are a few subtle &lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org/ledger.html&#34;&gt;differences&lt;/a&gt; between the two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signing PDFs via command line</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/signing-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/signing-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Signing PDFs in Linux is always a PITA. Part of the reason is that Adobe&#xA;stopped the development of a linux port of Adobe Reader since adobe reader v9.&#xA;Some of the newer PDFs require features which are newer than acrobat v9 and&#xA;cannot be opened or signed with acrobat v9.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this page, I summarize some of the options for signing PDF that have worked&#xA;for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local config for kitty</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the last &lt;a href=&#34;../changing-terminal-and-browser&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I am&#xA;testing out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sw.kovidgoyal.net/kitty/&#34;&gt;kitty&lt;/a&gt; as my terminal emulator instead of UXTerm. So for&#xA;everything has been smooth sailing except for one minor issue. On my work&#xA;desktop, I want fontsize 11 but on my laptop, I want fontsize 14. This is a combination of resolution and physical size of the two monitors. Reading the documentation of kitty.conf, it was not clear how to set conditional values for the variables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing terminal and browser</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time on the terminal: using alpine to send emails and using&#xA;vim/neovim to edit tex files and code. For at least a decade if not longer, I&#xA;have been using UXTerm as my terminal emulator. At some stage I spent some&#xA;time configuring UXTerm fonts and color schemes to what I like, and I have&#xA;been using it ever since. Recently, I started experiencing some weird issues&#xA;with UXTerm, which forced me down a rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing out Visidata</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with large spreadsheets. I do use simple&#xA;spreadsheets for keeping track of budgets/investments/taxes etc., but the only&#xA;big spreadsheets I encounter are sifting through all applicants for hiring&#xA;students and assigning grades to students. I struggle through OpenOffice Calc&#xA;to work through these, because navigating spreadsheets is too slow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a recommendation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visidata.org/&#34;&gt;visidata&lt;/a&gt; in a thread of&#xA;HackerNews, and it certainly looks like a program that I should checkout the&#xA;next time I need to work through a big spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Slack from the terminal</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/slack-tui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In rencent years, lot of my short conversations with my research lab has moved&#xA;to Slack. I am not a big fan of closed protocol communication clients, but&#xA;Slack has the advantage that it is relatively easy to use. Well, it seems that&#xA;it relatively easy to use for everyone except me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying Fish Shell</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/trying-fish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; as my shell for almost 15 years. I spent ages&#xA;configuring it in the beginning and for the most part I have been happy with&#xA;my setup. Lately, I saw multiple suggestions for&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-autosuggestions&#34;&gt;zsh-autosuggestions&lt;/a&gt;, which&#xA;has a tag-line &amp;ldquo;Fish-like autosuggestions for zsh&amp;rdquo;. Imitation is the best form&#xA;of flattery. So, I thought of giving fish a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
