<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLI on Tinkering with Linux</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/categories/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLI on Tinkering with Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/categories/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Local config for kitty</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/kitty-local-config/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in the last post, I am testing out kitty as my terminal emulator instead of UXTerm. So for everything has been smooth sailing except for one minor issue. On my work desktop, I want fontsize 11 but on my laptop, I want fontsize 14. This is a combination of resolution and physical size of the two monitors. Reading the documentation of kitty.conf, it was not clear how to set conditional values for the variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing terminal and browser</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/changing-terminal-and-browser/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time on the terminal: using alpine to send emails and using vim/neovim to edit tex files and code. For at least a decade if not longer, I have been using UXTerm as my terminal emulator. At some stage I spent some time configuring UXTerm fonts and color schemes to what I like, and I have been using it ever since. Recently, I started experiencing some weird issues with UXTerm, which forced me down a rabbit hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing out Visidata</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/linux-blog/post/visidata/</guid>
      <description>Normally, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with large spreadsheets. I do use simple spreadsheets for keeping track of budgets/investments/taxes etc., but the only big spreadsheets I encounter are sifting through all applicants for hiring students and assigning grades to students. I struggle through OpenOffice Calc to work through these, because navigating spreadsheets is too slow.
I recently came across a recommendation for visidata in a thread of HackerNews, and it certainly looks like a program that I should checkout the next time I need to work through a big spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
